Jose R. Velazquez Gonzalez

Johnson St., Victoria, BC, Canada | ⊠ joserobertovg@gmail.com | ② (778) 700-6364 | ⊒ https://analystjose.com/

Summary

Fast-learning business professional with 12+ years' experience in diverse industries, developing unique insights and strong analytical skills from operations to management. Enthusiastic about processing, analyzing, and interpreting data to identify key metrics to drive growth, using tools such as Excel, R, SQL, and Tableau.

Skills

Programming Languages: SQL, R (dplyr, ggplot, shiny), Python (Pandas, NumPy, matplotlib)

Software: Excel, Tableau, Tableau Prep, RStudio, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Jupyter Notebooks, Office 365

Work Experience

Online Sales at Vetta | Remote

Mar 2020 - Present

- Designed Tableau dashboards to perform a business analysis and present findings to stakeholders, focusing on Sales and AR.
- Built e-commerce stores (Shopify and Mercado Libre) including layout, themes, descriptions, images, and prices for 200+ products.
- Delivered prompt customer service on Messenger, WhatsApp, and e-mail, reducing response times to less than 1 hour.

Operations Auditor at Coppel | Zacatecas, Mexico

Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

- Analyzed individual store operations from the database to select unusual and/or suspicious operations to prevent fraud.
- Performed retail stores, warehouses, and distribution centers audits, evaluating performance, and generating auditing reports.
- Reviewed processes, documents, and inventories to generate a proper risk assessment for managers to make better decisions.

Insurance Agent at Seguros Monterrey New York Life | SLP, Mexico

Jul 2015 - Jan 2017

- Arranged meetings evaluate individual clients' needs and goals to create long-term savings, investing, and retirement plans.
- Explained in detail each individual policy coverage as per the current law of insurances and sureties.
- Certified insurance agent in Mexico by CNSF (National Insurance and Surety Commission).

Customer Service at Telcel | SLP, Mexico

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015

- Delivered outstanding face-to-face customer service, sales, quotation, billing, problem solving and client retention.
- Managed confidential information of hundreds of customers, creating and updating information on ERP.

Proprietary Trader | Remote

Dec 2011 - Present

- Traded diverse CFD's markets like Forex, Indices, Commodities, Futures, and Crypto, using a rule-based trading system.
- Used technical analysis including price action, market structure, moving averages, support and resistance, and supply and demand.

Administrative Assistant at Atena Bienes Raices | SLP, Mexico

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

- Processed documents, collected client information, and filled out loan approval forms with banks and government agencies.
- Created and updated an Excel database with hundreds of homes listings, for salespersons to easily access the properties features.

Education

Business Administration Certificate

University of Victoria | Victoria, B. C., Canada | Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

Business Intelligence and Data Analytics (BIDA) Certificate

University of Victoria | Victoria, B. C., Canada | Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

Bachelor of Business Administration

Minor in Finance | Universidad del Valle de Mexico | SLP, Mexico | Aug 2005 – Dec 2009